Yeah, I hear that there's a Hawaiian custom
something called a hukilau. Hukilau, hukilau is a
they have a roof, end of the roof they have a net there, they surround that.
a certain place and they drag the net. They surround it.
You mean they carry the net out?
Carry the net out.
How do they...
Something to keep the net floating?
Yeah, sometimes those floaters are floating.
Some of them were laid down on the bottom and they dragged the net in.
What do the floats, what are the floats made of?
The float made of those, uh...
Some coconut, dry coconut I guess.
Oh, dry coconut.
Yeah.
That's a two-strip coconut.
And that floats the top of the nail.
Couple.
on that. Now the word Lao means leaf doesn't it? Lao is a leaf.
It's a leaf.
All right.
But now, where does the leaf come in, in this world?
Okay, a lot of the leaves, you know, this is one of the top, top of the root.
so that when they pull, the fish is not going to jump over that rope.
The ropes, the leaves keep the fish from jumping over to the air that we're in.
Yeah, they're scared of my legs, but they want to go under the water, see?
The moment you go under the water, they...
They will go to the net. They have a pocket on the net.
They have a pocket on the net.
Then the bottom of the net. Bottom of the net have a pocket here.
The bottom must have a pocket.
They have some kind of things to make it sink.
Sink is a lid, they have a lid.
Oh, they have lid on it, I see.
Then somebody goes out and puts the net on.
out around. Yeah, they told him with a boat. With a boat. Yeah, two boats they go this
hour.
And then who pulls it in?
Well, they have a lot of girls from the shows, about 40-50.
you look at the guy is a cool little robber,
But they must have a pretty big school of fish there.
Yeah.
Once in a while they have a nice school.
all right and then they pull them all in and the fish
don't are scared to jump out so they get no they are eating up on a neck or a
They get caught in a net.
I suppose the top of the net comes in sooner than the bottom.
in the bottom, so if they do try to go out, they're not pocketed.
on you know about six or seven guys is swimming on it around the net to the
watching the
the fish going. Oh, I see. And then chasing at the hole.
Well, about how much fish did it get out of her?
Once I saw a white male, they caught about...
About a ton, I guess, of those Akule.
Oh, they have a nice crew.
What's the coolest?
Hmm...
The coolest...
Some kind of, you know, how I wish to call it, I couldn't, I didn't call it.
That's it.